careerstep.com 2016-05-08

# Privacy Policy

Last updated August 7, 2015 CAREER STEP is committed to protecting your privacy when you visit our website. To demonstrate our commitment to user privacy, we provide the following information describing the information we collect and store, how we might use that information, security measures to protect that information, and your rights regarding the way we collect and use that information. This Privacy Policy applies to the online collection of information at CAREER STEP’s website only. CAREER STEP reserves the right to amend or otherwise modify this Privacy Policy at any time. As such, you are encouraged to review this Privacy Policy from time to time for any changes. If a significant change is made, Career Step will give additional notice. 

## COLLECTION AND STORAGE

CAREER STEP collects and stores a variety of information from its website visitors. Some of this data is not personally identifiable and is collected and stored automatically via the use of cookies. A cookie is a small file that is stored on your computer’s hard drive and may contain the following information: • Your browser • Your Internet domain • Your computer's operating system • The links you followed to enter and leave our website • Your IP Address This information lets us see how users are finding our website and tells us which pages are visited most often. Cookies may also be used to recognize you and give you access to specific areas of our website. You can opt out of the use of cookies by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie, although doing so may impact your user experience. For more information on cookies, including how you can delete or reject cookies, please refer to your web browser help file. CAREER STEP collects and stores in our database certain personal information provided when you request information from us, communicate with us, or enroll in one of our courses. This information may include without limitation: name, address, email address, birth date, phone number, student ID, social security number, prior education, course enrollment/progress, grades, graduation status, financial status (tuition/fees balance). In addition we may collect your credit card number in order to process your enrollment and collect payment. We do not ever knowingly collect information from children under the age of thirteen, nor is our website designed to provide any service to children under the age of thirteen. If you are under thirteen, please do not give us any personal information. If you have reason to believe that a child has provided personal information to us, please contact us and we will attempt to remove that information from our databases. 

## USE OF INFORMATION

Non-personally identifiable information is used to help us improve our website by enabling us to discover and address the needs of our website visitors. This includes making our website accessible to the various web browsers and operating systems used to access our website. CAREER STEP may use third parties, including Google, to show you Career Step ads when you visit different sites on the internet. These third parties use cookies to collect non-personal information and show ads based on your prior visits to the Career Step website. You can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) or you can opt out of the use of cookies generally by having your browser disable cookies or warn you before accepting a cookie. However, opting out of Google's use of cookies or the use of cookies generally may impact your user experience. For more information on cookies, including how you can delete or reject cookies, please refer to your web browser help file. By supplying your contact information when requesting information or enrolling in one of our courses, you authorize CAREER STEP and its agents (outsource calls centers and academic partners) to contact you (using the information you provide to us) about CAREER STEP or its agent's products and services, including product releases and updates, seminars, events, surveys, trainings, and special offers. You can opt-out of future communications from Career Step by sending an email to [info@careerstep.com](mailto:info@careerstep.com) or calling 1-800-246-7837. Unless expressly prohibited by a student in writing, in furtherance of certain educational and job placement objectives, CAREER STEP reserves the right to release student email addresses to certain third parties in order for the student to request special training software included with enrollment and share student information on an as needed basis as follows: 

## TYPE OF INFORMATION:

| 

## AVAILABLE TO:  
  
---|---  
Program progress, graduation status and grades| Employer; Potential employer with whom a student has applied; Sponsor paying all or part of student fees; Third party resolution agencies; Third party organization through whom a student has enrolled with CAREER STEP  
Financial status (tuition/fees balance)| Sponsor paying all or part of student fees  
  
From time to time, CAREER STEP may be required to provide personal information in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law. Unless prevented by law, CAREER STEP will attempt to notify the student involved prior to any release of such information. This Privacy Policy does not apply to third parties with whom you may become involved in the process of enrollment with CAREER STEP or in the process of seeking employment. You are advised and encouraged to obtain applicable privacy policies of such third parties in order to know how they collect and use private information. 

## SECURITY

CAREER STEP website(s) have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. We utilize industry standard SSL encryption when accepting your credit card information during the online enrollment process. 

## STUDENT RIGHTS

CAREER STEP wants your information to be accurate and complete and recognizes that access and comment is necessary. You will not have the ability to change information on file, but may request a review or correction by either calling 1-800-246-7837 or emailing CAREER STEP at [privacy@careerstep.com](mailto:privacy@careerstep.com). You may also request that CAREER STEP not disclose your personal contact information to third parties.
